Guide to the Department of History, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records, circa 1940-1987; Accession 1997-A-080
  - Fellows of colleges, Morys, etc..., 1961 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - History department: membership lists, 1960-1962 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Placement, office policy problems, 1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Placement opportunities, 1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Yale graduates looking for jobs, 1952-1961 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Comprehensive exams and department majors, 1957-1959 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Placement, jobs recommendations (parts I and II), January to July 1962 (Box 32, Folder 23-24)
  - History poster, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Department miocell current, 1961-1962 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Course of study, 1961-1963 (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - Majors, honors, department exam, 1960-1962 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - Library problems, 1960-1962 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Publications, miscellaneous, YHP, 1957-1959 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Majors, course elections, 1955-1960 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Budget, schedule, course calculations, 1960-1961 (Box 33, Folder 2A)
  - Current, course elections, graduate enrollment statistics, 1957-1960 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Staffing calculations, 1957 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Advanced placement conferences, 1961 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - New courses and course descriptions, 1958-1961 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - History department, course of study; Yale College, 1958-1959 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Blue book course proof, 1958-1959 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Honors seminar, History, 1958-1962 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - History department current, 1960-1961 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Current, miscellany, 1957-1959 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Meetings of department, 1960-1962 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Notes of minutes of meetings, 1958-1960 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Personnel, faculty, visiting lecturers, 1949-1952 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Administration, rules on tenure, etc... leave of absence, salary scale, 1938-1939; 1947 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Faculty, leaves of absence, 1951 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Faculty retirements, 1951 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - History department faculty, general, 1950-1953 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Faculty, research in progress, 1951-1952 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Freshman instructors ratings, Undated (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Assistants in instruction, 1949-1950 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Employee medical examination report, 1959 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Personnel, faculty, visiting fellowships, 1939-1945 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Personnel, faculty, visiting fellowships, 1944-1949 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Administration, general, miscellaneous, 1945-1951 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Expense accounts, 1969-1970 (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - Administration, correspondence, odd information (parts I and II), 1940-1954 (Box 34, Folder 1-1A)
  - Expenses (parts I and II), 1958-1959 (Box 34, Folder 2-3)
  - Expenses, 1957-1958 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Expenses, 1960-1961 (Box 34, Folder 5-6)
  - Expenses, 1959-1960 (Box 34, Folder 7-8)
  - Expenses, 1956-1957 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Administration, (budget), bills and receipts, 1955-1956 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Rating scale for teachers, instruction appraisals, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Yale Historical Bulletin, 1964-1971 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Programs in International and Area studies, 1963-1967 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - European and British, 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Educational Services, inc., 1965 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Teaching appointments and alumni, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - African studies, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - American Historical Association (AHA), 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 17A)
  - Afro-American studies, 1969-1970 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Mortgage loan plan, September 1, 1968 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Grants and contracts, 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Clerical, 1968-1971 (Box 34, Folder 21)
  - Committee on Teaching and Learning, 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 21A)
  - Meeting minutes, May 19, 1964 (Box 34, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 23)
  - Financial situation and restriction of employment, September 9, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 24)
  - Recruitment, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 24A)
  - Chairs, 1969-1971 (Box 34, Folder 25)
  - Sale of equipment, 1971 February 15 (Box 34, Folder 25A)
  - Graduate student prizes, 1968 (Box 34, Folder 26)
  - Yale Historical bulletin, alumni, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 27)
  - Women in history, 1970-1972 (Box 34, Folder 28)
  - Undergraduate student prizes, 1964-1968 (Box 34, Folder 29)
  - Allan Nevins prize, 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 30)
  - President's luncheon, Undated (Box 34, Folder 33)
  - Junior faculty summer research grant, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 34)
  - Leaves, 1971-1972 (Box 34, Folder 35)
  - Leaves, 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 36)
  - Leaves, 1968-1969 (Box 34, Folder 37)
  - Leaves, 1969-1970 (Box 34, Folder 38)
  - Leaves, 1968-1969 (Box 34, Folder 39)
  - Leaves, 1967-1968 (Box 34, Folder 40)
  - Faculty leaves, 1964-1965 (Box 34, Folder 41)
  - Hall report college seminars, 1968-1969 (Box 34, Folder 42)
  - Student work and appointments, 1966-1967 (Box 34, Folder 44)
  - Recommendations, 1964-1965 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Lectures, 1970-1971 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Lectures, 1969-1970 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Leaves and appointments, housekeeping and supplies, funding and salaries, 1963-1971 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Modern European search committee, Undated (Box 35, Folder 51)
  - History of Technology, position applications, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 59)
  - Chestnut diary finance, 1979-1981 (Box 35, Folder 79)
  - Chestnut diary, graduate student employment, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 80)
  - Chestnut diary, graduate student employment, 1977 (Box 35, Folder 81)
  - Chestnut diary, graduate student employment, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 81A)
  - Chestnut diary, summer employment (South Carolina), 1977 (Box 35, Folder 82)
  - Chestnut diary, summer employment (South Carolina), 1978 (Box 35, Folder 83)
  - Correspondence, chestnut diary, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 84)
  - Woodward, C. Vann (CVW), syllabi, book lists, 1975-1976 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Free Expression at Yale, members (addresses), Undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Committee on Freedom of Expression at Yale, financees, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Committee on Freedom of Expression at Yale, minutes, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Copies of recommendations, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Written statements submitted to committee and notes from open meeting, 1972-1975 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Reactions to published report, 1975 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Committee on the Freedom of Expression at Yale, press clippings, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Documents, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Documents about the work of the committee on free expression at Yale, 1963-1974 (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Documents (including Stanford), 1974 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Committee memos to deans and their answers, 1970-1974 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Excerpts from report of national commission on causes and prevention of violence, Undated (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Yale College undergraduate regulations, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Princeton, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - University of Chicago (Shils), 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Issue of media, the press (Chauncey), 1974 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Kagan's speech on "Freedom of Speech at Yale", Undated (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Clippings about Freedom of Expression outside Yale, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Report, Part I, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Report, Part II, history, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Report, Part III, policy, 1974 (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - Committee's final report (drafting), 1972 (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Final committee report, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - OAH (Organization of American Historians)-AHA (American Historical Association) inquiry, 1965-1979 (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - Petty cash, 1959-1979 (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - Promotion renewal, November 9, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - Appointment renewals, 1976-1977 (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - Provost's office, teaching assignments and course list (for budget preparation), 1978-1983 (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - Courses taught, committee assignments, essays and dissertations supervised, 1978-1979 (Box 36, Folder 29A)
  - Courses taught, committee assignments, essays and dissertations supervised, 1977-1978 (Box 36, Folder 30)
  - Courses taught, committee assignments, essays and dissertations supervised, 1976-1977 (Box 36, Folder 31)
  - Annual report, 1990-1991 (Box 36, Folder 32)
  - Annual report, 1989-1990 (Box 36, Folder 33)
  - Annual report, 1987-1988 (Box 36, Folder 34)
  - Annual report, 1986-1987 (Box 36, Folder 35)
  - Annual report, 1985-1986 (Box 36, Folder 36)
  - Annual report, 1984-1985 (Box 36, Folder 37)
  - Annual report, 1983-1984 (Box 36, Folder 38)
  - Annual report, 1982-1983 (Box 36, Folder 39)
  - Annual report, 1980-1981 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Annual report, 1979-1980 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Office space, 1986-1987 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Office assignments, 1984-1986 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Space utilization, 1983-1984 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Office space, 1982-1983 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Office space, 1981-1982 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Office space, 1980-1981 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Office space and assignments, 1977-1978 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Office space, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Office space, 1977-1978 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Biennial space survey, 1983 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Space function survey, 1979-1981 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Departmental space function surveys, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Syllabi, 1976-1977 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - American History Advisory committee, 1969-1970 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - History department advisory committees (American, English, and European), 1970-1971 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous HRL, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Urban studies bulletin, 1970 (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1971-1973 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous, 1966-1967 (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - Receipts and expenditures, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Gottlieb, archives, 1958-1962 (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Metzdorf, archives, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 31A)
  - Yale archives, 1958-1962 (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - Library, 1958-1962; 95 (Box 37, Folder 33)
  - Library, seminar, etc..., 1957-1961 (Box 37, Folder 34)
  - Committee in humanities, 1954-1961 (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - Graduate school faculty, 1961-1962 (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - Yale graduate school, policy questions, 1960-1961 (Box 37, Folder 37)
  - Africa, 1961-1962 (Box 37, Folder 38)
  - American studies, 1957-1958 (Box 37, Folder 39)
  - Chairman American History, 1958-1959 (Box 37, Folder 40)
  - American studies, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 41)
  - Appointments, official resignations (parts I and II), 1956-1961 (Box 37, Folder 41A-41B)
  - President A. Whitney Griswold (AWG), 1956-1962 (Box 37, Folder 42)
  - Notices from Secretary Holden, 1957-1959 (Box 37, Folder 43A)
  - Notices from graduate school, September 5, 1961 (Box 37, Folder 45)
  - Brewster, Kingman, 1961-1962 (Box 37, Folder 46)
  - Notices from the Provost, 1956-1962 (Box 37, Folder 47)
  - Negotiations with Provost, 1957-1959 (Box 37, Folder 48)
  - Notices from Yale College dean, 1958-1959 (Box 37, Folder 49)
  - Travel allowance and grants, 1959-1962 (Box 37, Folder 50)
  - Institute of Social Science, 1968-1971 (Box 37, Folder 51)
  - American Historical Association, 1968-1969 (Box 37, Folder 53)
  - Yale University press, books published, 1966-1971 (Box 37, Folder 54)
  - Requests for nominations, Modern European History, 1963-1964 (Box 37, Folder 55)
  - History grad program, 1967-1968 (Box 37, Folder 56)
  - Latin American studies, 1967-1969 (Box 37, Folder 57)
  - Posters and flyer, 1963-1965 (Box 37, Folder 58)
  - Job recommendations for graduate students, 1965-1966 (Box 37, Folder 59)
  - Job openings elsewhere, 1964-1965 (Box 37, Folder 60)
  - Job openings, 1969-1970 (Box 37, Folder 61)
  - University directives, 1962-1969 (Box 37, Folder 62)
  - Visiting lecturers, 1968-1969 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Fourteenth Yale conference on the teaching of Social Studies, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Yale College reactions to Divisional and Intensive Majors, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - History 89 financing, 1965 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Freshmen, averages, placements, 1967 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - 574A-31-55617, P. Gay, fund psychoanalytic research, 1984-1985 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Department list, 1972-1975 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Faculty list, with office hours, 1970-1971 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Faculty list, 1968-1969 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Faculty list, 1967-1972 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Bulletin information, 1959-1971 (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Angell, Kay, 1961 (Box 38, Folder 15A)
  - Courses and undergraduate course of study, 1963-1964 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - History department memorabilia, 1958-1962 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Visitors and lecturers, 1958-1959 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous statistics, 1961-1962 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Library policy, problems, 1962-1963 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - General University administrative directives, 1962-1963 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Personal, 1964 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Inter-University ratings, etc..., 1957-1960 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Special appropriation, 1958 (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - Budget projections (in 1966) for 1972 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - Annual report, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - Annual report, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - Annual report, 1969 (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - History department, number of majors, miscellaneous, 1968-1970 (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - Black Panther (May 1st) rally, Undated (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - Yale atlantic community of scholars, St. Anthony, 1968 (Box 38, Folder 33)
  - Yale historical publications services, 1969-1970 (Box 38, Folder 34)
  - Student advisory committee to history department, 1966-1970 (Box 38, Folder 35)
  - Concilium, 1967-1968 (Box 38, Folder 36)
  - American studies, 1969-1970 (Box 38, Folder 37)
  - Urban studies, 1968-1970 (Box 38, Folder 38)
  - University course staff, 1965-1966 (Box 38, Folder 39)
  - Faculty offices, 1958-1962 (Box 38, Folder 40)
  - Office equipment and supplies, 1958-1962 (Box 38, Folder 41)
  - Fellowships, 1961-1963 (Box 38, Folder 42)
  - Faculty, leaves, ranks, sabbaticals and salary scale, 1959-1962 (Box 38, Folder 43)
  - Appointments, 1961-1962 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Chairman's expenses, 1962-1963 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Junior faculty summer research support, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Undergraduate curriculum, 1968-1969 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - History department information and new major proposals, 1967-1968 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Faculty information, 1970-1971 (Box 39, Folder 45)
  - Faculty lists, 1975 (Box 39, Folder 47)
  - British History, 1971-1972 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Chairs, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - American History, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - History department committees, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Faculty appointments, funding proposals, 1971-1972 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Asian studies conference, 1967-1969 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Visiting lecturers, 1969-1970 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Possible faculty appointments, 1968-1970 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Graduate programs in History, policy documents, 1957-1959 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Yale Ph.D. questionnaire, 1960-1961 (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Letters on Ph.D questionnaire, 1960-1961 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Ph.D. questionnaire tabulations, Undated (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Report on Yale's Ph.D. in History reconsidered (parts 1 through 9), 1961 (Box 40, Folder 13-21)
  - Complete strike file (parts 1 and 2), 1984-1985 (Box 40, Folder 22-23)
  - National endowment for the humanities, nominations for summer stipends, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - NEH summer grants, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 25)
  - Report, sub-committee to review the college seminar program, 1976 (Box 40, Folder 26)
  - Report, committee on teaching in the residential colleges, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 27)
  - College seminars, fall, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 28)
  - College seminars, spring, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - College seminars, fall, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - College seminars, spring, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 31)
  - College seminars, fall, 1984 (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - College seminars, spring, 1984 (Box 40, Folder 33)
  - College seminars, fall, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 34)
  - College seminars, spring, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 35)
  - College seminars, fall, 1982 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - College seminars, spring, 1982 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - College seminars, fall, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - College seminars, spring, 1981 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - College seminars, fall, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - College seminars, spring, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Visiting lecturers in Yale College, fall, 1979 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Visiting lectures in Yale College, spring, 1979 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Visiting lecturers in Yale College, fall, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - College seminars, spring (visiting lecturers in Yale College or History department), 1978 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Visiting lecturers in Yale College, fall, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Visiting lecturers in Yale College, spring, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Visiting lecturers in Yale College, 1976-1977 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Visiting lecturers in Yale College, 1975-1976 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Visiting lecturers in Yale College, 1974-1975 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Visiting lecturers in Yale College, 1973-1974 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Visiting lecturers in Yale College, 1972-1973 (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - History education project (A.H.A.), 1969-1978 (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Carnegie teaching fellowships, 1965-1969 (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Carnegie teaching fellows, 1963-1964 (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Student employment, 1976-1977 (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Student employment, 1973-1974 (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - Bursary assistance, 1972-1973 (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - Afro-American History, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - Department policy, provost and chairman, 1972-1973 (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - Bulletin copy, 1976-1977 (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Yale Historical Bulletin, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - Yale Historical Bulletin, replies, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 30)
  - Affirmative action, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 31)
  - Affirmative action, Blum report, Undated (Box 41, Folder 32)
  - Summer term inquiry, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 33)
  - Concilium and chairs, 1976-1977 (Box 41, Folder 34)
  - Concilium faculty grants, 1978-1979 (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - Junior faculty salaries, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 36)
  - Undergraduate major review, 1974-1975 (Box 41, Folder 37)
  - Committee, undergraduate program, 1977 (Box 41, Folder 38)
  - Graduate curricular reform, 1975-1976 (Box 41, Folder 39)
  - Committee on graduate program, 1977-1978 (Box 41, Folder 40)
  - Graduate adv. committee, 1976-1977 (Box 41, Folder 41)
  - Appointments review procedure, 1976 (Box 41, Folder 42)
  - Teaching loads, 1975-1977 (Box 41, Folder 43)
  - Committee on point 8, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 44)
  - Course committee, 1977-1978 (Box 41, Folder 45)
  - Catalogue of films, 1978 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Course committee, 1977-1979 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Advisory committee, Undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Advisory committee, 1977-1978 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Film committee, 1976-1978 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Junior seminar guidelines, 1978 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Undergraduate student advisory committee, 1975-1976 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Admissions applications, inter-office correspondence, 1978-1980 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Appointment procedures, 1978-1979 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Search procedures, 1978-1979 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Announcement of one year jobs, 1978-1979 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Medieval search, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - French History, May 3, 1976 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Colonial United States, 1978-1979 (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Chinese fill-in, 1979-1980 (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - British, 19th and 20th century, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Reviews of APs, 1979-1980 (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - Provost, 1979-1980 (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - Budget, 1979-1980 (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - Leave policy TLA, 1976 (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - Announcements (deputy?), 1978-1979 (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - Writing intensive courses, 1978-1979 (Box 42, Folder 27)
  - Special programs, Humanities, 1977-1979 (Box 42, Folder 28)
  - Teaching fellows, 1979-1980 (Box 42, Folder 29)
  - American studies, teaching fellows, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 30)
  - Andrews Society, 1978-1979 (Box 42, Folder 31)
  - Sophomore advisors, 1979-1980 (Box 42, Folder 32)
  - College courses, 1979-1980 (Box 42, Folder 33)
  - Graduate students in graduate programs, 1978-1979 (Box 42, Folder 34)
  - History graduate course schedule, advisors and advisees, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 35)
  - Graduate school, 1978-1979 (Box 42, Folder 36)
  - Graduate admissions, 1979-1980 (Box 42, Folder 37)
- Administrative records of Robin Winks as chair of the Dept. of History, circa 1996-1998; Accession 2001-A-045
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2033
  - Alumni news, reunion edition, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - History department, graduate alumni reunion, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Graduate reunion RSVP correspondence, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Post reunion correspondence, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lost alumni, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
  - Photographs, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Records of the Dept. of History reunion, 1998; Accession 2001-A-100
  - Dept. of History reunion records, 1998 (Box 1)
- Report of the Library Committee of the Dept. of History, 1969; Accession 2001-A-183
  - Report of the Library Committee of the Dept. of History, 1969 April 16 (Box 1)
- Records of William Cronon concerning environmental studies, 1988-1990; Accession 2002-A-072
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2025
  No inventory available.
  - Event posters, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - YSEC meeting minutes, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Faculty information sheet, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Funding proposal for the Yale Environmental Center, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Information studies for major proposal, March 22, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Urban Issues, URI newsletter, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yale student environmental coalition newsletter, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Green corps, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Teaching fellows, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Freshman outdoor orientation trip (F.O.O.T.), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - In the Rough, written by Williams, Florence, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Noble Foundation proposal, Studies in the Environment at Yale University, draft 2, March 29, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Course of study committee, studies in the environment, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Noble Grant proposal draft for renewed and expanded funding for Studies in the Environment, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Report for the Noble Grant and correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Records of William Cronon concerning environmental studies, circa 1983-1990; Accession 2002-A-181
  - Yale Environmental Network (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Yale Environmental Network: Response forms (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - loose papers (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - EDF-Yale Institute (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - SE General items, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Studies in the Environment (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Initial committee (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Original proposal (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Grants (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Meeting minutes, agendas (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Misc. correspondence (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Student Environmental Coalition (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Labor contract negotiations, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - TA solidarity (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - FOOT Program (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Personnel records of faculty, 1958-1997; Accession 2003-A-065
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2073
  - Professors
    - Ahlstrom-Gabriel (Box 1, Folder 1)